MORGAN ROHAN

0413 486 761 morganrohan@outlook.com

Buderim, QLD

PROFILE

I am an innovative thinker who backs up creative problem solving with hard work and an appetite for knowledge. As an employee I like to balance 'let's get this done' with 'how can we do this better?'. My technical skills and knowledge run deep, but I value the opportunity to know more and not remain within a single niche. I would say my biggest asset is my ability to approach a project or task with considerations at both the micro and macro levels; the intricacies and details of a single aspect as well as how they combine to a whole or expand beyond just my contribution.

EXPERIENCE OVERVIEW

SENIOR TECHNICAL OFFICER, SNAPSIL CORPORATION, 2017-present

I initially started as a casual sample maker at Snapsil and now have the title of Senior Technical Officer, which encompasses a broad range of responsibilities and makes use of my materials engineering knowledge and skills. Snapsil is a packaging development and design company and the primary focus of my role is in material research and development, particularly in using flexible plastics to thermoform. Day to day responsibilities also include IP development and management, keeping up to date and understanding of standards and advancements within the FMCG and pharmaceutical packaging spaces, data interpretation and analysis, formal research and reporting, along with working closely with our Senior Industrial Designer and international partners.

It is the role that contributes the most to my professional career, however each workplace and role has provided valuable learnings that I have carried along with me. Further details of this role and others can be found over the page or I am more than happy to answer any questions.

EDUCATION OVERVIEW

DIPLOMA OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, AIT 2022

- Focus on full stack development, website building and general ICT

DIPLOMA OF ENGINEERING, TAFE Queensland 2021

- Qualification as engineer with focus on chemical and materials science

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR TECHNICAL OFFICER, SNAPSIL CORPORATION — JAN 2017 - Present

As a technical officer, my role is multi-faceted and includes responsibilities across the areas of engineering materials, technology creation and development, intellectual property understanding and development, design and information technology. It requires a comprehensive understanding of the entire Snapsil process, from conceptualisation through to commercialisation and the ability to communicate this to customers, suppliers and third parties.

More specific responsibilities of my role include:

- Testing and validation of designs and materials internally, as well as at international partner facilities.
- Facilitating and conducting third party analytical testing including electron microscopy, sterilisation, transport and regulatory testing as well as analysis and reporting of data outcomes.
- Leading materials development processes, including selection, testing and quality assurance processes.
- Increasing the understanding of the technologies and geometries associated with the packaging, with a particular focus on how this affects product delivery an potential upscaling.
- Ongoing Intellectual Property research and development, with a focus on creation of new IP as well as managing the risk associated with current holdings.
- Leading the thermoforming and manufacturing process understanding for the Technical functions, as well as being responsible for internal lab equipment management and maintenance.
- Understanding of FMCG and Pharmaceutical packaging sectors, as well as developing and maintaining professional connections within the space.
- Crossover with the Senior Industrial designer to help design and alter packs for customer consideration, as we'll as adjustments and improvements to design relative to the material requirements.
- Leading the management of and interactions with third party suppliers to maintain a very high level of security with regards to information technology, especially focusing on document sensitivity and data recovery.
- Expertise in running the machinery associated with each step of production, encompassing multiple machine systems and components.
- Development and management of internal technical procedures and processes as well as resources.

FREELANCE CREATIVE, SELF EMPLOYED - 2020 - PRESENT

Since 2019 I have grown and maintained a presence on social media that has lead to opportunities for content creation and freelance journalism. My specific niche is around beauty products, such as makeup, skincare and haircare and remains completely separate to my other employment. I create my own visual content (images and videos) for my accounts, along with a fortnightly SubStack newsletter I produce. I have a portfolio showcasing some of the paid work I have created that I am happy to provide, as well as the articles I write for online women's media publication Mamamia.

This has helped me develop a range of skills around social media and communication, as well as administrative and business practice. My ability to help develop websites from a functional point of view meets my ability to create interesting content that has the ability to engage and educate.

SENIOR SALES STAFF, QBD THE BOOKSHOP - SEPT 2011 - DEC 2018

I started in this position as a junior staff member whilst in school and progressed to the senior staff member title in 2014.

The responsibilities of this position included stocking shelves, merchandising to company standards, customer service with a focus on sales, POS service system and general store maintenance.

The additional responsibilities in my role as a senior staff member included managing more junior staff on a shift, receiving stock and processing documentation, financial functions such as end of day reporting and cash management, inter store communications and management of customer experience, including the authority to process refunds or create stock transfer.

ASSISTANT MANAGER, CHOCOLATE COUNTRY - MAR 2015 - NOV 2015

This started as a casual position of three days per week and within two months I was made Assistant Manager, leading to an increased five days per week including fully managing weekend trade days.

The responsibilities of this position included stock management, customer service, POS systems service and weekend staff management. I worked in both the retail and cafe sections of the store, which required food preparation processes, as well as barista and waitress training.

The additional responsibilities in my role as assistant manager included being solely responsible for weekend trade and staffing, processing stock orders, financial functions such as end of day reporting and the training of new staff members. During my time in this role, I also implemented several processes such as a new ordering and stock management system, staff requests, better healths and safety practices in the kitchen and a new POS system incorporating barcoding and stock level reporting.

EDUCATION

DIPLOMA OF ENGINEERING - TECHNICAL — TAFE QUEENSLAND, 2021

It acknowledges my skills across core engineering concepts, my specialisation into chemical and materials engineering, as well as my ability to work in a professional engineering environment. The course itself covers a comprehensive theoretical and semi-technical base for working as an engineer and as such, the recognition of course work completed in addition to my skills from working in the industry.

DIPLOMA OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY — AIT, 2022

An acknowledge of my skills specifically in the area of web and software development, as a full stack developer. It was a condensed delivery of a full diploma course and focused on back end skills such as database construction and management, building functionality and information handling as well as front end skills like user experience, interface creation or use of common frameworks and building relational links between both. I am specifically skilled in the use of HTML and CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React and the MERN stack.

CONTINUED SELF-EDUCATION

This includes specifically upskilling in the areas of intellectual property creation and management, programming and web development, software design and use, as well as good business and operational practices. I have personally been seeking out online courses and similar resources to improve my knowledge and applicable skills in these areas.

QUEENSLAND CERTIFICATE OF EDUCATION — SUNCOAST CHRISTIAN COLLEGE, 2014 Formal recognition of completing high school through Year 12 in Queensland.

SKILLS

- Engineering mindset, encompassing a wide array of chemical and materials knowledge and ability to problem solve and think critically.
- Adaptability, within my daily role to balance responsibilities as well as when working in unfamiliar vendor settings under resource pressures.
- Macro and micro project thinking, able to envisage the 'big picture' or a project, as well as separating into weekly or daily tasks.
- Ability to communicate, both internally to convey knowledge and processes as well as externally to build and maintain domestic and international professional relationships.
- Enthusiasm and passion for my work, which drives me to want the very best from myself.
- High level of technical skills in a range of areas, including 3D modelling and CAD programs, modelling and computation through MATLAB and Excel, as well as extensive chemical and materials knowledge and understanding.
- High level of web and software development skills, including competency in the use of JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MERN stack and API integration as well as using Git workflow and Agile project management methodology.

REFERENCES

Neil Cashman

CEO, Snapsil Corporation

Phone: 0418 149 910 Email: cashmanneil@yahoo.com.au

Paul Cavu

Technical Director, Snapsil Corporation (direct manager)

Phone: 0488 029 828 Email: paulcavu@yahoo.com.au

Tariana Murchie

Worked together previously at QBD The Bookshop, was frequently my shift manager

Email: tariana.murchie@gmail.com

WHO I AM OUTSIDE OF WORK

- I am a passionate foodie, enjoying both eating and cooking, using my spare time to challenge myself with recipes or new skills. One of my favourite things to do outside of work is cook for family and friends as well as exploring new local eateries.
- I have forever been an avid reader and enjoy it in all forms, from several shorter form newsletters to classic and contemporary fiction.

•	I enjoy all kinds of personal fitness, but particularly running as it provides a great way for me to manage my stress and mental health. I also enjoy pilates and playing recreational tennis, as well as enjoying any opportunity to attend live sports.